Pedro Laranjinha Casimiro

CHAMUSCA, SANTARÉM, PORTUGAL

plcasimiro2000@gmail.com | github.com/p-laranjinha | linkedin.com/in/p-laranjinha

ABOUT ME

Software engineer with 6+ years of experience in backend, frontend, testing, developer tooling, pipelines and infrastructure as code. Passionate about all programming related parts involved in creating a useful or interesting product, including backend, frontend, testing, and others. Most experienced with Typescript and Python but also interested in doing either Go, Zig or C# professionally.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - API Mocking with Chaos Engineering $Sonae\ MC$

Sep 2022 - Jul 2023 Aveiro, Portugal

- Developed an internal Mockoon fork that exposes a runtime interface to specify and add latency and chaos to API mocks for facilitating future improvements in software resilience.
- Created a GitHub repository workflow that automatically verifies and deploys mocks to Microsoft Azure.
- Created a GitHub organization with a certain structure and workflows in place to facilitate the creation of repositories with the above workflow for any amount of teams.
- Created documentation and lead presentations on the relevance of mocks and chaos engineering, as well as how to use Mockoon and the repositories and organization I created to all of the company's development and QA teams.
- Additionally worked on maintenance tasks for .NET and Typescript projects.

Software Developer

Sep 2022 - Jul 2023

Aveiro, Portugal

 $WIT\ Software$

- Internship for my Master's Degree's dissertation.
- Created multiple prototypes resembling the Vodafone TV video streaming application in multiple web frontend frameworks to run on Smart TV's with the Tizen operating system (Samsung TVs).
- Developed a Puppeteer script that connects to the Smart TV and automatically tests and collects metrics on all web frontends used.
- Analysed the metrics obtained in order to figure out the easiest method to migrate an existing React Native application onto Smart TV devices while having the application be performant.

SKILLS

Expertise: Agile Development, API Development, Android Development, Chaos Engineering, CI/CD Pipelines, Concurrent Programming, Containerization, Data Structures & Algorithms, Database Systems (SQL & NoSQL), Distributed Systems, Infrastructure as Code, Software Design Patterns, Software Security, Software Testing, Web Development

Programming Languages: Bash, C#, C, Dart, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Java, Nix, PowerShell, Python, SQL, TypeScript

Technologies/Frameworks: Cuda C, Django, Docker/Podman, Expo, Flutter, Git, Java Spring, Kubernetes, LightningJS, Linux, Microsoft Azure, Mockoon, .NET, NixOS, NodeJS, Puppeteer, React, Selenium, SolidJS, Tizen, Userscripts, web-vitals

Languages: Portuguese (native), English (proficient, obtained B2 certification in highschool)

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Informatics Engineering | 17/20 Grade University of Aveiro

 $Sep\ 2021$ - $Sep\ 2023$

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering | 17/20 Grade University of Aveiro

Sep 2018 - Sep 2021